Now, a Multinomial Distribution is simply
多项分布是二项分布
a generalization of the binomial distribution to more than two values.
向多个值的泛化
For example, let's say we have newspaper articles and
例如 假设有新闻报道和三个主题
three topics: science, politics, and sports.
分别是科学 政治和体育
Let's say each topic is assigned randomly to the articles, and when we look,
假设每个主题随机分配给这些文章
we have three science articles,
有三篇科学文章
six politics articles, and two sports articles.
六篇政治文章和两篇体育文章
So, for a new article,
对于一篇新文章
what would the probability be that it's science, politics, or sports?
它是科学 政治或体育文章的概率是多少？
We would imagine it's a bit higher for politics and science,
可以想象它是政治和科学文章的概率高些
and higher for science and sports.
并且是科学和体育文章的概率也高些
This is not for sure,
不确定
but it's likely to happen.
但是很有可能发生
So now, these three probabilities live in
这些概率位于一个三角形中
a triangle where if we pick a point than any of the corners,
如果选择角落中的某个点
it means the probability for that topic is one,
则该主题的概率是 1
and the others are zero,
其他主题的概率是 0
and if we pick it in the middle,
如果选择中间的点
then the probabilities are similar for the three topics.
则三个主题的概率相似
So, maybe the probability density distribution
因此 这三个概率的概率密度分布
for these three probabilities will be like this one here,
可能是这样的图形
since articles are more likely to be politics than anything else,
因为文章更有可能是政治文章
and less likely to be sports than anything else.
不太可能是体育文章
This probability density distribution is calculated with
这个概率密度分布的计算方式是
a generalization of the formula for the Beta distribution given here.
采用这个 β 分布的泛化公式
It's called a Dirichlet distribution.
称之为狄利克雷分布
Again, there is no reason for these numbers to have to be integers.
同样 这些数字并非必须是整数
For example, if we have 0.7, 0.7,
例如 如果是 0.7 0.7 和 0.7
and 0.7, this is the Dirichlet distribution.
这是狄利克雷分布情况
It's hard to see, but the density function is very
当我们非常接近三角形的角落时
high when we get really close to the corners of the triangle.
密度函数变得非常高 虽然不太容易看出这一规律
Meaning that any point picked randomly from
表明从这个分布中随机选择的任何点
this distribution is very likely to fall either at the science,
非常有可能落入
politics, or sports corners,
科学 政治或体育所在角落
or at least close to any of the edges,
至少接近任何一条边
and very unlikely to be somewhere in the middle.
位于中间某个位置的可能性非常低
Here are some samples of Dirichlet distributions with different values.
这些是具有不同值的狄利克雷分布示例
Notice that if the values are large,
注意 如果值很大
the density function is high in the middle,
则密度函数在中间很高
and if they're small, it's higher in the corners.
如果值很小 则在角落很高
If the values are different from each other,
如果值各不相同
then the high part moves towards the smaller values,
则更高的部分移向更小的值
and away from the larger values.
并离开更大的值
This is how they look in 3D.
这是三维图形
So, notice that if we want a good topic model,
如果要创建很好的主题模型
we need to pick small parameters like the one on the left.
我们需要选择很小的参数 例如左侧图形
This is how we'll pick our topics from now on.
接下来我们将这么选择主题